<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>InheritNOW</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 18:38:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.8</generator>

<image>
	<url>/wp-content/uploads/2021/04/cropped-favicon@512x512-32x32.png</url>
	<title>InheritNOW</title>
	<link>/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
	<item>
		<title>Is an Inheritance Taxable?</title>
		<link>/is-an-inheritance-taxable/</link>
					<comments>/is-an-inheritance-taxable/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[david]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 19 Aug 2021 18:29:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=1001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As a wise man once said, nothing is certain but death and taxes. That wise man, by the way, was Founding Father Benjamin Franklin. If a relative of yours has recently followed old Ben to the great beyond, both death and taxes may be on your mind—namely how much tax will the government Mr. Franklin...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As a wise man once said, nothing is certain but death and taxes. That wise man, by the way, was Founding Father Benjamin Franklin. If a relative of yours has recently followed old Ben to the great beyond, both death and taxes may be on your mind—namely how much tax will the government Mr. Franklin helped create put on my inheritance? The answer, as with anything tax related, depends on a number of factors including which state the deceased lived and what your relationship to them is. While the short answer is yes an inheritance is taxable, depending on your particular situation you could pay nothing, or you could pay as much as 18% of the value of the inheritance.</p>



<p>Your inheritance <em>can</em> be taxed in two ways, from two different collectors. Your inheritance can be subject to an inheritance tax and an estate tax, by the federal government and/or the state government. Some good news: you’re only responsible for paying inheritance tax, as the estate tax comes directly out of an estate, during the probate process, before funds are distributed. More good news regarding the federal government: In most cases, assets you receive as a gift or inheritance are not taxable income at the federal level. However, if the assets you inherit later produce income (like earning interest or dividends, or you collect rent from a property), that income is likely taxable and up to you to report. Thirdly, in this good news trifecta, you will only be subject to an inheritance tax if you live in one of these six states: Iowa, Kentucky, Maryland, Nebraska, New Jersey, or Pennsylvania. How much tax you owe depends on your relationship to the deceased—surviving spouses generally pay nothing, and children pay either nothing or very low tax rates. The tax rate typically increases the more distantly related you are. Here is the max inheritance tax rate for each of the states with an inheritance tax:</p>



<ul><li>Iowa: 15%</li><li>Kentucky: 16%</li><li>Maryland: 10%</li><li>Nebraska: 18%</li><li>New Jersey: 16%</li><li>Pennsylvania: 15%</li></ul>



<p>The inheritance tax is only levied by states, but both the federal government and states may collect estate tax. However, the federal estate tax only applies to estates that are worth more than $11.7 million (as of 2021). Twelve states and the District of Columbia levy their own estate taxes, with rates starting as low as 10% in Connecticut, and increasing as high as 20% in Washington state. And the estate tax is paid before your portion of the inheritance is passed on to you, so you don’t have to pay it.</p>



<p>Having said all that, the main thing is this: Beneficiaries generally don&#8217;t have to pay income tax on money or other property they inherit, aside from the exceptions described above and on money withdrawn from an inherited retirement account (IRA or 401(k) plan).</p>



<p>If you are due a large inheritance, be sure to study the laws in your state. It is also recommended to consult with a financial advisor who can help you put your inheritance to work for you in the smartest way possible. If you need your inheritance funds sooner than 1.5 years (the average length of probate in the USA), you may consider an inheritance advance. <a href="/your-inheritance-advance/">Click here for more info on that option.</a></p>



<p>Sources:</p>



<p><a href="https://www.nerdwallet.com/article/taxes/inheritance-tax">Nerd Wallet</a></p>



<p><a href="https://smartasset.com/retirement/is-inheritance-taxable">Smart Asset</a></p>



<p><a href="https://www.alllaw.com/articles/nolo/wills-trusts/must-pay-income-tax-inherited-money.html">All Law</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/is-an-inheritance-taxable/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What You Need to Get an Inheritance Advance.</title>
		<link>/what-you-need-to-get-an-inheritance-advance/</link>
					<comments>/what-you-need-to-get-an-inheritance-advance/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[david]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 16 Jul 2021 20:28:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=749</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you are going to inherit money or assets from an estate and would like to receive those funds sooner, and avoid waiting months or years for the probate process, you may have already learned about the option of an inheritance advance. There are companies out there, like InheritNOW, who are willing to advance you...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you are going to inherit money or <a href="/glossary/#assets">assets</a> from an estate and would like to receive those funds sooner, and avoid waiting months or years for the <a href="https://continuedpath.com/wills-probate/">probate process</a>, you may have already learned about the option of an inheritance advance. There are companies out there, like InheritNOW, who are willing to advance you a portion of your inheritance in exchange for a fee that is collected when probate closes.</p>



<p>Here’s how an inheritance advance works: First, the company who provides the advance confirms the value of your inheritance. They then make you an inheritance advance offer—advancing you a percentage of your entire inheritance for a fee, which is &nbsp;collected after the <a href="/glossary/#estate">estate</a> closes. Once you agree, you tell them how much you’d like advanced and they send you the funds right away. You get the money fast, and they do all the waiting for the estate to close. At that time, the company collects their fee, and you receive the balance of your inheritance.</p>



<p>But what do you need to get an inheritance advance started? In order for a company to offer you an advance, they need to assess and confirm the value of your inheritance. They can do this quickly with some key bits of information, including:</p>



<ul><li>Information relating to a probate case including the probate case number, court name and location.</li><li>Name and contact information of the <a href="/glossary/#executor">executor</a> and/or estate attorney, we can then gather the following information from them:<ul><li>The death certificate of the deceased person from whom you will inherit</li><li>The <a href="/glossary/#will">will</a>, if you have it (not always necessary, but helpful)</li><li>The mortgage statement of any real estate that is included in the inheritance</li><li>Appraisal report of any real estate included in the inheritance</li><li>Appraisal report for any business included in the inheritance</li></ul></li></ul>



<p>That’s all you need to apply for an advance on your inheritance. Remember, an inheritance advance is not a loan—it is simply your inheritance money delivered sooner—so there are never any payments to make, or anything to pay back whatsoever.</p>



<p>If you would like an inheritance advance offer for your inheritance, click here. There is no fee to receive an offer for an inheritance advance.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/what-you-need-to-get-an-inheritance-advance/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Pandemic + Probate = More Wait</title>
		<link>/pandemic-probate-more-wait/</link>
					<comments>/pandemic-probate-more-wait/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[david]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 24 Jun 2021 22:35:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=500</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[If you’ve ever been involved with an estate after the death of a loved one or friend, you know first-hand that probate is the legal process of settling an estate, and can be painfully slow.  During the pandemic, this painful process slowed to new lows.  During the pandemic, for public safety reasons, courts across the...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>If you’ve ever been involved with an estate after the death of a loved one or friend, you know first-hand that <a href="/glossary/#probate">probate</a> is the legal process of settling an estate, and can be painfully slow.  During the pandemic, this painful process slowed to new lows. </p>



<p>During the pandemic, for public safety reasons, courts across the country and around the world have either operated on limited hours with reduced staff or shut down completely. Things are starting to get better, and as the rest of society slowly reopens and the pandemic recedes and court systems reopen, it&#8217;s clear the effect on legal processes, like probate, will take longer to move at &#8220;pre-pandemic&#8221; speed. In fact, the probate process in the United States has gone from an average of 16 months to 24 months to complete.</p>



<p>The extended delays in closing estates and distributing <a href="/glossary/#assets">inherited assets</a> to <a href="/glossary/#beneficiary">beneficiaries</a>—which was already a lengthy and frustrating experience for people counting on those inheritance funds—have caused many to look to firms providing <a href="/your-inheritance-advance/">inheritance advances</a>. Although advances of this kind have been around for over a decade, it remains a relatively unknown option for beneficiaries who may need or want the cash sooner. While many need the cash to pay for various expenses there are those who simply don’t want the family drama which often goes along with the probate process. An inheritance advance, or what some call “<a href="/your-inheritance-advance/">probate cash</a>” can provide inheritance advances to any beneficiary with a verifiable inheritance. The most appealing aspect of an inheritance advance is that it is not a loan, and thus does not require repayment. </p>



<p>So, if you are stuck waiting for your inheritance to complete the lagging probate courts, an inheritance advance is an excellent option.</p>



<p>An inheritance advance from InheritNOW allows you to receive inheritance funds immediately. Simply by providing your name and a few details related to the estate, you could find out quickly what kind of an advance you could receive.  The best feature of an inheritance advance, sometimes called <a href="/your-inheritance-advance/">probate advance</a>, is that it is not a loan. It is the purchase of an agreed-upon percentage of the money you expect to inherit, which means you receive the money that was meant for you; so you are not required to make any monthly payments or repay any of the amount of the advance you receive. InheritNOW assumes the risk and then waits for the estate&#8217;s probate to close, in the end, we are reimbursed directly from the estate only when probate is finally settled. So, you get your money now while we do all the waiting and risk-taking.</p>



<p>If you’re looking for inheritance funding, putting your inheritance money to work for you now, please give InheritNOW a call or contact us <a href="/">here</a> and we will evaluate your inheritance and make you an immediate <a href="/your-inheritance-advance/">inheritance cash advance</a> offer.</p>



<p>We look forward to helping you inherit now.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/pandemic-probate-more-wait/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How I Got My Inheritance Before Probate Was Finished.</title>
		<link>/how-i-got-my-inheritance-before-probate-was-finished/</link>
					<comments>/how-i-got-my-inheritance-before-probate-was-finished/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[larry]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 2021 19:07:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://avx056.wpengine.com/?p=246</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When my Dad passed away after a long battle with cancer, in a way it was a relief and his suffering was finally over, but I was not prepared for the impact it would have on me personally. Fortunately, I had a brother who I could rely on to make all the funeral arrangements because...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When my Dad passed away after a long battle with cancer, in a way it was a relief and his suffering was finally over, but I was not prepared for the impact it would have on me personally. Fortunately, I had a brother who I could rely on to make all the funeral arrangements because I could not face it. A week or so after the funeral we quickly had to start making decisions about his estate and what he left behind. I was still in a fragile state and simply couldn’t bear the thought of working through his financial past, as I&nbsp;wanted to get past the pain without thinking about what to do with what he left behind. While researching what to do after someone dies, my brother found out about inheritance advances—something I didn’t even know existed.</p>



<p>I learned a lot of interesting information.</p>



<p><strong>It’s Not a Loan&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>We found out that there are companies that provide inheritance advances, which do not need to be paid back since they are not loans.&nbsp;These companies assess the value of the estate and the likelihood of probate closing, then they advance the money.&nbsp;These companies make their money when probate finally closes and collect the portion that’s agreed on in the contract. &nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>It Could Bring Me Peace of Mind</strong></p>



<p>Even though my dad’s will was very clear, I soon learned that probate was going to take much longer than I expected. I think it had something to do with a second mortgage on his house. I certainly trusted my brother to handle the details fairly, but the fact remained that I really needed that inheritance cash as soon as possible. I have a son in college and was hoping the inheritance money would help pay for his next semester. An inheritance advance was exactly what I needed.</p>



<p>I looked around online and went with a company that seemed easy to work with and had a short form on their website ready to be completed. According to my research, this company took a smaller percentage than other companies.</p>



<p>After I filled out their form, they emailed me back right away to schedule a call. On the call, the&nbsp;representative walked me through how the process works (it’s really simple) and asked me some questions about my dad’s estate. She was able to tell me immediately that I could get an advance on my inheritance&nbsp;as long as the information I’d given them was correct.</p>



<p><strong>My Mediocre Credit Score Didn’t Matter Because – No Credit Checks</strong></p>



<p>I was worried that my bad credit rating would be a problem, but a credit check was not required, they just looked at the estate that is in probate. All that mattered was the value of my dad’s estate and some legal issues around that (like was he indeed the owner of his house, etc.). She listed off the documents they needed to see and told me how to get them to her.</p>



<p>After the call I got copies of the few documents I needed, took pictures of them with my phone and uploaded them to the website; then I waited, but not for long. I received an email the next day saying they’d be happy to give me an advance on my inheritance and could have it wired directly to my checking account. </p>



<p><strong>The Dollars and Sense of My Advance</strong> </p>



<p>Here are the details of my inheritance cash advance: They estimated the value of my inheritance to be $160,000 and said they could advance me up to 40% of it if I wanted, or I could opt for a lower advance amount if I chose, and wait for probate to end to receive the rest. I’d rather have the cash now, so I went for the full $65,000. After some research of other competitors, their fees were clearly the most fair, so I accepted. Just like they promised, the money appeared in my checking account in <strong><u>two days</u></strong>. </p>



<p>I paid for the last semester of my son’s school, planned a trip with my wife for this summer, and put the rest away for a rainy day. My brother decided not to get an advance. Nine months later he is still waiting for probate to be resolved and the estate to close, which means dealing with more frustration on top of missing our dad.</p>



<p>Overall, I’m very happy with the service I received. The inheritance advance allowed me to put my inheritance to work right away, while saving me from months of worry and paperwork. When my son graduates this fall, I’ll be thinking of how my dad helped make it possible.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/how-i-got-my-inheritance-before-probate-was-finished/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
